Register of the Robert Alfred Theobald papers, 1908-1959
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert Alfred Theobald papers
1908-1959
1942-1957
60010
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes (5.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, war diaries, dispatches, operations plans and orders, manuals, service lists, memoranda, reports, and war estimates relating to naval operations in Alaska from May 1942 to January 1943, including the Japanese invasion of the Aleutians, June 1942, and the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor.
Theobald, Robert A. (Robert Alfred), 1884-1957.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1960.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1884 January 25 Born, San Francisco, California
1902-1903 Attended University of California
1903-1906 B.S., U.S. Naval Academy
1908 Commissioned Ensign, U.S. Navy
1917-1918 Gunnery Officer, U.S.S. New York, Flagship of U.S. Squadron with British Grand Fleet
1918 September Promoted to Commander
1919-1921 Executive Officer, Naval Post Graduate School
1922-1924 Destroyer Command, Asiatic Fleet
1924-1927 Commanding Officer, Naval Post Graduate School
1927-1929 Executive Officer, U.S.S. West Virginia
1930-1932 Secretary of War Plans, Navy Department and Member of Joint Army - Navy Planning Committee
1932 February Promoted to Captain
1932-1934 Chief of Staff, Destroyers, Pacific Fleet
1934-1935 Member of Advanced Class, Naval War College, engaged in seminar study of Japan and Pacific War
1935-1937 Strategy Division, Naval War College
1937-1939 Commanding Officer, U.S.S. Nevada
1939-1940 Chief of Staff, U.S. Fleet
1940 Spring Member, General Board, Navy Department
1940 June Promoted to Rear Admiral
1940 Summer Commander, Cruiser Division Three
1940-1941 Commander, Flotilla One, Destroyers, Pacific Fleet
1941 December - 1942 May Commander, Destroyers, Pacific Fleet
1942 May - 1943 January Commander, Northern Pacific Force, in Alaska Operations
1943-1944 Commandant, First Naval District and Navy Yard, Boston
1945 Retired from active service
1954 Author, The Final Secret of Pearl Harbor
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, war diaries, dispatches, operations plans and orders, manuals, service lists, memoranda, reports, and war estimates relating to naval operations in Alaska from May 1942 to January 1943, including the Japanese invasion of the Aleutians, June 1942, and the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor.
United States. Navy--Officers; Pearl Harbor (Hawaii), Attack on, 1941.; United States--Armed Forces.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Aleutian Islands.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Personal Correspondence, 1943-1957 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - Alexander, Ensign William H., 1943
  - Associated Newspapers, Inc., 1955
  - Bledsoe, Captain A. M., 1943-1944
  - Brooks Bros., 1943
  - Burke, Arleigh (Chief of Naval Operations), 1957
  - Burwell, Commodore Louis E., 1944
  - Carlson, Lieutenant A. W., 1943
  - Cluverius, Rear Admiral (Ret.) Wat Tyler, 1943-1944
  - Collins, Edward T., 1943
  - Craig, Captain W., 1943
  - Crooker, Mrs. Doris Theobald, 1943
  - Cushing, Cardinal, 1944
  - Davis, Frank W., 1944
  - Dawson, N. E., 1944
  - Doggett, Professor L. A., 1944
  - Dykes, James, 1944
  - Erskine, W. J., 1943-1944
  - Fernety, Lieutenant Bolice P., 1944
  - Fahrion, Captain F. G., 1944
  - Fitz, Reginald, 1944
  - Forrestal, James (Secretary of the Navy), 1943-1944
  - Gehres, Commodore L. E., 1943
  - Graham, Jennie Theobald, 1943
  - Grosskopf, Ensign Homer L., Jr., 1943
  - Higgins, George T., CQM, USN, 1943
  - Hill, Robert W., 1943
  - Howell, James B., 1943
  - Huebl, Commander Roland M., 1944
  - Jones, Dr. Chester M., 1957
  - Jones, Mrs. Dan W., 1943
  - Kalbfus, Admiral E. C. (Commander Destroyers, Battle Force), 1934
  - Kimmel, Rear Admiral (Ret.) Husband E., 1943-1957
  - King, Fleet Admiral Ernest J., 1948
  - King, Captain Ogden, 1943
  - Knox, Frank (Secretary of the Navy), 1943
  - Lahey, Thomas B., 1943-1944
  - Leary, Vice Admiral N. F., 1944
  - Lowell Associates, 1943
  - Ludewig, Commander J. W., 1943
  - McCown, Captain H. Y., 1943
  - McKay, Lt. Commander Baxter M., 1943
  - McMorris, Rear Admiral C. H., 1943
  - McMurdie, Phillip C., 1943
  - Military Historical Society of Massachusetts, 1943-1944
  - Moring, Captain T. S., 1944
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1948
  - Murray, Mr. and Mrs. Norbert, 1943
  - Myer, Harold, 1943
  - Office of Price Administration (Boston, MA), 1944
  - O'Rourke, Jonn, 1943
  - Pennypacker, J. A., 1944
  - Phillips, William (former Ambassador to Italy), 1947
  - Pierce, Reverend Michael G., S.J., 1943
  - Read (periodical), undated
  - Reifkohl, Captain F. L., 1943
  - Reilly, Lt.-Colonel James A., 1943-1944
  - Ryan, Boatswain Vernon L., 1943
  - Santos, J. B., 1943
  - Simon, Frank J. (Secretary-Treasurer, Master Mechanics Association, Naval Ship Yard, Boston, MA), 1947
  - Simons, Captain R. B., 1943
  - Slocum, Major B. C., 1943
  - Smith, Commander and Mrs. Steele B., 1944
  - Smith, Talbot, 1943-1944
  - Sporting News (periodical), 1944
  - Theobald, Robert A., Jr., undated
  - Thompson, H. Keith, 1957
  - United Press (Boston, MA Bureau), 1943
  - Vincent, Ensign Robert G., 1943
  - Wagner, Rear Admiral F. D., 1943
  - Walters, Lt.-Commander H. C., 1944
  - Wang, K. S. (Consulate of the Republic of China), 1948
  - Wessendorf, Mr. and Mrs. Homer, 1943
  - Who's Who in the Western Hemisphere, 1944
  - Windle, Lt. (j.g.) W. T., 1943
  - Winslow, Mrs. Mary W., 1944
  - Winterhalter, Harold, 1944
  - Withers, Rear Admiral T., 1943
- Speeches and Writings, 1943-1959 (Boxes 1-7)
  Articles, books, and speeches, arranged as listed, then chronologically thereunder. Includes correspondence and book reviews related to these works.
  - Articles, 1947-1957
    Newspaper clippings of articles written by Robert A. Theobald for a biweekly column in the Beverly Evening Times, "Horizons in World and National Affairs."
    - 1947 January 26-June 27 (Box 1)
    - 1947 July 8-December 24
    - 1948 January 3-July 3
    - 1948 July 7-November 10 (Box 2)
    - 1949 January 4-June 29
    - 1949 July 2-December 31
    - 1950 March 4-December 27
    - 1951 January 3-December 29
    - 1952 January 5-December 31 (Box 3)
    - 1953 January 3-December 30
    - 1954 January 6-December 30
    - 1955 January 5-December 31
    - 1956 January 4-June 30
    - 1956 July 7-December 29
    - 1957 January 5-April 24 (Box 4)
  - Books, 1945-1959
    - Death of a Navy, by Andrieu d'Albas (1957), 1955-1957
      Translated from the French and with an introduction, maps, and notes by Robert A. Theobald.
      - Correspondence, 1955-1957
        - D'Albas, E. Andrieu, 1955-1957
        - Deland, Frank S., 1957
        - Devin - Adair Co., Publishers, 1955-1957
        - Fitzgerald, William H. G., 1957
        - Parker, Capt. R. C., 1957
        - Pearne, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd. (London), 1956
        - Robbins, Rear Admiral Thomas H., Jr., 1957
      - Supplementary materials to text: maps, notes, charts, etc.
    - The Final Secret of Pearl Harbor (1954), 1949-1959
      - Book reviews
      - Correspondence, 1949-1959
        - Unidentified, 1954
        - Abbot, Stephen, 1959
        - Allen, Joe M., 1954
        - Anderson, Henry W., 1954
        - Anderson, Paul F., 1954
        - Ashley, Clinton N., 1954
        - Askins, William F., Sr., 1959
        - Atkins, John B., 1954
        - Babbitt, Captain H. S., 1954
        - Babcock, Frederick (Editor, Magazine of Books, Chicago Tribune), 1954
        - Bacon, B. B., 1954
        - Ball, William H., 1954
        - Ballinger, Alice (Mrs. Webster), 1954
        - Ballinger, Webster, 1954
        - Ballinger, Willis, 1954
        - Baltzly, Commander (Ret.) Frederick, Sr., 1954
        - Barnes, Harry E., 1953
        - Barnes, Stuart C., 1954
        - Barroll, Henry H., 1954
        - Barry, William O., 1954
        - Bauer, A. J., 1954
        - Begin, Z. L., 1954
        - Belknap, Rear Admiral Reginald R., 1954
        - Bemis, Samuel F., 1954
        - Bennett, Milo O., 1954
        - Bequette, J. C., 1954
        - Berryhill, Mrs. M. B., 1954
        - Bertocki, Mrs. Mary A., 1954
        - Bierly, Charles R., 1954
        - Blum, Herman, 1954
        - Bragg, Colonel (Ret.) C. H., 1954
        - Braveman, David, 1954
        - Brewer, Basil, 1954
        - Bridgett, Charlie, 1954
        - Browne, Kenneth, 1954
        - Buckley, J. L., 1954
        - Butler, Dr. Harry H., 1954
        - Burke, Lt.-Commander (Ret.) John H., 1954
        - Calhoun, Admiral W. L., 1954
        - Callahan, Robert J., Jr., 1954
        - Callahan, Robert J., Sr., 1954
        - Campi, Reverend Vincent L., 1957
        - Cannings, Fred E., 1954
        - Capponi, John, 1954
        - Carlton, Miss Marjorie, 1954
        - Castle, William R., 1954
        - Cecil, Dr. Arthur B., 1954
        - Chase, Reverend Harry E., 1954
        - Choat, Harry, 1954
        - Church, Frederic C., 1954
        - Clark, Rear Admiral David H., 1954
        - Coburn, Commander (Ret.) Frederic G., 1954
        - Colegreave, Kenneth, 1954
        - Collins, E. D., 1954
        - Collins, Edward M., 1954
        - Colombel, John J., 1954
        - Combier, P. Hodges, 1954
        - Comstock, Captain L. Wells, 1954
        - Connors, Thomas K., 1954
        - Cooke, George P. and Sophie J., 1954
        - Coolidge, William A., 1954
        - Covington, Captain (Ret.) H. S., 1954
        - Crist, Lt.-Colonel (Ret.) Arthur P., 1954
        - Daley, Robert F., 1953
        - Daley, Robert L., 1954
        - Dalton, Lt.-Colonel Arthur T., 1954
        - Dartnell, R. B., 1954 (Box 5)
        - Davidson, Eugene (Editor, Yale University Press), 1952
        - Davy, Commander Charles G., 1954
        - DeArmond, Lt. (Ret.) George W., Jr., 1954
        - DeBurgh, R., 1954
        - Deland, Frank S., 1949-1953
        - Dement, Merritt H., 1954
        - Dickenson, Denny D., 1956
        - Diemer, Mrs. Anne F., 1954
        - Donavin, Lt.-Commander K. H., 1954
        - Dorney, H. Jackson, 1954
        - Downes, Captain Oliver L., 1954
        - Duffey, Walter E., 1954
        - Du Pont, Mrs. Marcella M., 1953-1954
        - Eckels, Richard P., 1954
        - Ehman, George C. (Athenian - Nile Club, Oakland, CA, President), 1954
        - Ettinger, Captain George M., 1954
        - Fairbank, Robert, 1954
        - Feeley, J. Richard, 1954
        - Fernety, Lt.-Commander Bolice P., 1954
        - Finch, J. D. (Chairman, Freedom Club, First Congregational Church of Los Angeles), 1954
        - Fischer, Marion, 1954
        - Flammer, Mrs. Betsy, 1954
        - Flint, Elder B. C., 1954
        - Flynn, John T., 1954
        - Folsom, Charles, 1954
        - Foote, P. W., 1954
        - Fuchs, Maria, 1954
        - Gagner, Beatrice (Mrs. Walter), 1954
        - Garrity, Devin A. (President, the Devin-Adair Co.), 1953-1957
        - Gatch, Thomas L., 1953
        - Glassford, Dodie, 1954
        - Glassford, Vice Admiral William, 1954-1957
        - Graves, F. L., 1954
        - Greaves, Percy L., Jr., 1954
        - Grenfell, Russell, 1954
        - Griffin, Robert, 1954
        - Grigg, Bessie, 1954
        - Grigsby, Joseph D., 1954
        - Grimm, Mrs. Verna B. (Librarian, the American Legion National Headquarters), 1954
        - Gruelick, Commander R. W., 1954
        - Haight, Rear Admiral (Ret.) Stanley M., 1954
        - Hall, James L., 1955
        - Halsey, Fleet Admiral William F., Jr., 1953
        - Harmon, Lt.-Commander (Ret.) Lloyd M., 1954
        - Harris, Walden E., 1954
        - Harrison, Ralph E., 1954
        - Hart, Mrs. Charles Spencer, 1954
        - Hart, Merwin K., 1954
        - Hassenkampf, Bruce H., 1954
        - Heaoner, Henry D., 1954
        - Heere, Leonard, 1957
        - Hefferan, Rear Admiral (Ret.) John B. (Director of Naval History, Dept. of the Navy), 1954
        - Hession, James M., 1954
        - Hession, L. S., 1954
        - Higham, Marritt, 1954
        - Hill, Major-General Jim Dan, 1954
        - Hodder, James R., 1954
        - Horan, Frank, 1954
        - Horton, J. J., 1954
        - Hoyt, Lawrence W., 1954
        - Houtz, Phillip (Executive Director, National Jewish Hospital at Denver), 1954
        - Humphrey, Churchill and Martha, 1954
        - Imperial War Museum, London, 1954
        - Isherwood, Mrs. Harry, 1954
        - Jennings, George C., 1953
        - Johl, Colonel Max G., 1954
        - Jones, Myron A., CRM (Ret.), U.S.N., 1954
        - Jones, William M., 1956
        - Joseph, Jerome, 1954
        - Kahala, Mrs. Aino, 1954
        - Kahn, David (President, New York Cipher Society), 1954
        - Keep America Committee, 1954
        - Kiesling, Clarence E., 1954
        - Killion, Robert H., 1954
        - Kitts, Vice Admiral Willard A., III, 1954
        - Klawans, Paul G., 1954
        - Knox, Commodore Dudley W., 1954
        - Kuhnle, Howard A., 1954
        - Lahey, Thomas B., 1954
        - Landes, Carl K., 1954
        - Lavender, Robert A., 1952
        - Lawrence, David (Editor, U.S. News and World Report), 1954
        - Leydon, Commander John K., 1954
        - Lilly, Herbert D., 1954
        - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1957
        - Lindsay, Commander Stewart, 1954
        - Lowry, Vice Admiral (Ret.) Frank J., 1954 (Box 6)
        - Lucas, Frances B. (Mrs. James C.) (Executive Secretary, National Society, Daughters of the American Revolution), 1955
        - Ludewig, Rear Admiral Joe W. and Minerva, 1954
        - McCabe, Hilton H., 1954
        - McCurdy, Florence, 1954
        - McDonald, Chester, 1954
        - McDonald, Irving T., 1954
        - McWilliams, John, 1954
        - Magoun, F. Alexander, 1954
        - Maraspin, Dana G. (Governor, Society of Colonial Wars in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts), 1954
        - Marr, Francis J. (Councillor, City Council of Lynn, MA), 1954
        - Mason, Frances E., 1954
        - Mercer, R. W., 1954
        - Mills, Lt.-Commander (Ret.) Charles A., 1954
        - Montgomery, Robert H., 1954
        - Moore, Alice, 1954
        - Morgan, Roy L., 1954
        - Morrison, Jay, 1957
        - Moseley, Major-General George Van Horn, 1954
        - Mulford, Allen, 1954
        - Nelson, Laurence E., 1957
        - Neustader, L. W., 1954
        - O'Donnell, John, 1953
        - Padrick, E. B. (Chairman, Armed Forces Fellowship Committee, Rotary Club of Chicago), undated
        - Paine, John B., Jr., 1954
        - Paisana, Finca, 1954
        - Palmer, Paul (Executive Editor, The Reader's Digest), 1954
        - Parker, Captain Ralph C., 1954
        - Parsons, Charles, 1954
        - Pascual, Pacifico T., 1954
        - Patterson, Donald M., 1955
        - Paynter, Thomas G., 1954
        - Pier, H. W., 1954
        - Polowsky, Joseph, 1954
        - Porter, Jesse B., 1954
        - Powell, Rear Admiral Paulus P., 1954
        - Power, James H., Jr., 1955
        - Proctor, Joseph R., 1952
        - Pyne, Rear Admiral S. N., 1954
        - Ralston, Byron B., 1954
        - Reynolds, Mrs. G. Bergen, 1954
        - Rhodius, H. U., 1954
        - Richards, Ira, 1954
        - Richardson, Admiral James O., 1953-1954
        - Rinehart, Mary Roberts, 1954
        - Rodgers, Margaret H. (Mrs. Anthony G.), 1954
        - Rogers, Captain Winifred, 1954
        - Ruggles, William B. (Editor, The Dallas Morning News), 1954
        - Ruhtenberg, Mrs. Jan, 1954
        - Rutherford, Alexander, 1954
        - Rutherford, S. Morton, 1954
        - Ryan, Russell C., 1954
        - Sakahura, T., 1954
        - Salouka, Beulah G., 1954
        - Sampson, William J., Jr., 1954
        - Schnitzer, George C., Sr., 1954
        - Schroeder, H. L. (Director, The Schroeder Foundation), 1954
        - Schwartz, Irving P. (Dept. of Public Relations, Queens College), 1954
        - Seebeck, Volney, 1954
        - Sharp, Capt. (Ret.) W. D., 1954
        - Shattuck, S. F., 1954
        - Sherry, Edward J., 1954
        - Short, Isabel Dean (Mrs. Walter C.), 1954
        - Simmons, Edward ( The Standard-Times, New Bedford, MA), 1954
        - Skorvaga, Elizabeth A., 1954
        - Smith, Vice Admiral William Ward (Poco), 1954
        - Spencer, Ensign Herbert, 1954
        - Stafford, Colonel (Ret.) Ben, 1954
        - Stafsing, Ivar, 1954
        - Steefel, Lawrence D., 1954
        - Strassburger, R. B., 1954
        - Streu, Niels Henning, 1954
        - Sullivan, Colonel (Ret.) Alexander C., 1954
        - Swanton, Hobart P., 1954
        - Taeni, John, 1954
        - Tanner, W. R., 1954
        - Taylor, Bradley R., 1954
        - Thayer, Mr. and Mrs., 1953
        - Theobald, A. J., 1954
        - Theobald, Chester A., 1954
        - Theobald, Ralph E., 1954
        - Theobaldt, Mrs. Anni Schwarz, 1954
        - Thomas, Irene J., 1954
        - Thornton, R. S., 1954
        - Timmons, Bettie Edmonds, 1954
        - Tong, H. K., 1956-1957
        - Traut, Capt. (Ret.) F. A., 1954
        - Trohan, Walter (Correspondent, Chicago Tribune), 1954
        - Trundle, Mrs. I. F., 1954
        - Turner, Edward R., 1954
        - Vansant, Stephen S., 1955
        - Warner, Louis D., 1954
        - Warren, Dale (Houghton Mifflin Co.), 1952
        - Warshauer, Charles S., 1954
        - Welch, Rachel (Mrs. James), 1954
        - Wessendorf, Homer W., 1954
        - West, Ralph E., 1954
        - Whittemore, George A., 1954
        - Whittemore, K. Robert, 1954
        - Williams, John C., 1954
        - Wygant, Captain Benyaurd B., 1954
        - Yarnell, Admiral (Ret.) H. E., 1953-1954
        - Zemke, Captain (Ret.) Eric, 1954
        - Zochert, Roland W., 1954
      - Printed copy (U.S. News and World Report), 1954 April 2 (Box 7)
    - "A World Seeks Peace,", 1945; Typewritten carbon copy of an unpublished manuscript.
  - Speeches and addresses, 1943-1945, 1956, undated
    - Outline for an unidentified speech, undated; Typewritten draft and typewritten carbon copy.
    - Address to workers of the Boston Navy Yard and South Boston Naval Drydock, undated; Typewritten and hand-written draft.
    - Address to Naval Graduating Units, Harvard University, 1943; Typewritten draft.
    - Response to the toast The United States Navy at the Annual Dinner of the Ancient and Honorable Artillery Company of Massachusetts, 1943 June 7; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Address to workers of the Boston Navy Yard and South Boston Naval Drydock, 1943 July 15; Typewritten draft.
    - Address at Presentation of Army and Navy "E" Award to Boston Navy Yard at Boston Garden, 1943 August 20; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Address at Commissioning of U.S.S. Wasp, 1943 November 20; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Interview with Admiral Theobald on radio program Life to the Front, station WEEI, 1943 December 8; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Radio talk by Rear Admiral Theobald over station WHDH, 1944 January 1; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Statement for the Boston newspapers, 1944 June 6; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Radio script for V-Day, 1945; Typewritten carbon copy.
    - Address before the Men's Corporate Communion Grace Church in Salem, Massachusetts, 1956; Typewritten draft.
- War Diaries, Commander North Pacific Force, Task Force Eight, U.S. Pacific Fleet, 1942-1943 (Boxes 7-10)
  Ships' logs and transcripts of radio dispatches, arranged chronologically.
  - 1942 May 22-31 (Box 7)
  - 1942 June
  - 1942 June (cont'd.) (Box 8)
  - 1942 July
  - 1942 August
  - 1942 September
  - 1942 October (Box 9)
  - 1942 November
  - 1942 December (Box 10)
  - 1943 January 1-3
- Naval Career Office File, 1908-1949 (Boxes 10-13)
  Dispatches, inventory reports, manuals, memoranda and reports, Navy Department correspondence and orders, operations plans and orders, service lists, and war estimates, arranged as listed, then chronologically thereunder. See also: Declassified U.S. Government Records.
  - Dispatches, 1942
    - Assistance Information and Data Acquisition Center (AIDAC) dispatches, 1942 May 16-22 (Box 10)
      These consist of decoded messages between Commander-in-Chief Pacific Fleet (CINCPAC) and Commander Northwestern Sea Front (COMNOWESTSEAFRON), concerning Japanese operations against Midway and the Aleutians.
    - Dispatches from the Commander of Task Force 8 to the Commander of Task Group 8.1 and the Commanding General of Eleventh Air Force, Fort Greely, Alaska, 1942 June-July, November-December
  - Inventory reports, Inventory Reports of Registered Secret and Confidential Publications Distributed by the Chief of Naval Operations, 1943-1944
  - Manuals, 1940-1942
    - Staff Manual, Cruiser Division Three, Battle Force, United States Fleet, 1940
    - Staff Instructions, Destroyer Flotilla One, United States Pacific Fleet, 1941
    - Staff Instructions, Destroyers, Battle Force, United States Pacific Fleet, 1942
    - Sound Military Decision, U.S. Naval War College, Newport, RI, 1942
  - Memoranda and reports, 1942-1944
    - Report from Headquarters of 11th Air Force Air Striking Group (Task Group 8.3), Kodiak, Alaska to Commanding General, Alaska Defense Command, Fort Richardson, Alaska (Box 11)
      Summary of operations to June 10th, 1942 (tactical employment of 11th Air Force in first phase of Japanese invasion of Aleutians), with relevant dispatches and notes.
    - Memorandum on the situation in Alaska, 1942 July 2
      Written by Admiral Theobald for the Commandant of the Thirteenth Naval District at the latter's request for information on the Alaska situation.
    - Memorandum of Comtaskforce 8 concerning the proposed relocation of Headquarters of Fleet Air Wing Four to Adak, circa 1942 September
    - "Planes Used in Kiska Mission,", 1942 September 14-December 18
    - "Analysis of Command Relationship Between Commander Task Force Eight and Commanding General Eleventh Air Force,", 1942 December 14
    - Memoranda on the grounding of the U.S.S. Alexander J. Luke, 1944 March 24
      Written by the Commander-in-Chief of the United States Fleet and Chief of Naval Operations, Fleet Admiral Ernest J. King, for the Commandant of the First Naval District, Rear Admiral Robert A. Theobald.
  - Navy Department correspondence and orders, 1908-1949
    Includes orders from, and correspondence with, Fleet Admiral Chester W. Nimitz (CINCPAC), Fleet Admiral Ernest J. King (COMINCH), Frank Knox (Secretary of the Navy), Franklin D. Roosevelt (as acting Secretary of the Navy and as President), Major-General Simon Bolivar Buckner, Rear Admiral Randall Jacobs (Chief of the Bureau of Navigation), and others.
    - 1908-1939
    - 1940-1949
  - Operations plans and orders, 1942
    - CINCPAC, No. 28-42, May 21
    - Comtaskforce 8
      - No. 1-42, May 27
      - No. 2-42, May 29
      - No. 3-42, May 31
      - No. 4-42, June 10
      - No. 5-42, June 22
      - No. 6-42, undated
      - No. 7-42, July 8 (Box 12)
      - No. 8-42, July 14
      - No. 9-42, August 1
      - No. 10-42, August 21